TIH SAMUEL MBIYIMO'O

Software Engineer

Involved in software development for more than 4 years, I have been working as a design and development engineer for more than 3 years in the Spring and Angular environment. Having gained a lot of experience in different environments, I have developed a strong knowledge of software architecture, software lifecycle management, and development.

WORK EXPERIENCE SKILLS

Associate Software Engineer

SCI 2M, Yaoundé, Cameroon — June 2018 till now

- Design and development of an e-wallet platform with a payment gateway integrating local payment methods such as Orange Money or MTN Mobile Money.
- Design and development of a reservation module for residents of company-owned homes.
- Design and development of a curative maintenance module for residents
- Took part in the development of Android mobile applications for the company's staff to assist them in their daily tasks.
- Design and development of a transversal invoicing module producing accounting documents and communicating with the other modules in a microservices architecture.
- Regular maintenance of the modules and development of new ones according to the company's needs.

Full-Stack Developer, Professional Internship

Hadron SA, Yaoundé, Cameroon — August 2017 till March 2018

- Improved data security by adding a mask that filters data according to the role and the logged-in user.
- Development of usage forms in asset management procedures.
- Addition of a business process management engine in the management of the material acquisition cycle.
- Work carried out according to the agile methodologies "Scrum" and "Kanban".

Engineering Internship

Hadron SA, Yaoundé, Cameroon — February 2017 till June 2017

- Needs analysis and design of the workflow engine
- Development of the workflow engine based on the WfMC (Workflow Management Coalition) guidelines
- Application of design patterns where appropriate.

Pre-engineering internship

Megasoft, Yaoundé, Cameroon — June 2016 till September 2016

 Installation and configuration of a strategic monitoring tool "Website Watcher" to monitor sites with potential markets for the company.

SICILLO

Programming Languages

samuel.tih@outlook.com
(+237) 6 56 76 04 88

(+237) 6 53 58 33 11

(iii) /samuel-tih/

(in) Samuel-tih

Samuel-tih

Sammie.tih

- Java
- Python 3
- TypeScript
- HTML
- CSS/Sass
- JavaScript
- Dart

Libraries and Frameworks

- Spring
- Angular
- React
- Vue
- Next
- Nuxt
- Django
- FastApi
- FlutterJest
- JUnit
- Cucumber
- Mockito

Tools and Platform

- Git
- Vite
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- Serverless
- Docker
- GitHub
- GitLab
- Jenkins
- Jira

Design

- Framer
- Figma

 Maintenance of the information system by making corrections to the email system.

Developer

Global EduPals, Yaoundé, Cameroon — May 2016 till August 2017

- Planning and drafting of project documents according to the "PRINCE II" methodology
- Design and implementation of a platform for data collection and assistance to community agents in rural areas.

Chief Technical Officer

Uzenze, Yaoundé, Cameroon — January 2018 till now

- Designed and built various applications for clients and for the company.
- We developed an application to track the availability of blood bags in various hospitals and an application for car rentals.
- We develop websites with WordPress or Joomla CMS for our clients.

EDUCATION

National Advanced School of Engineering Polytechnic, Yaoundé -

2012 - 2017

Computer Engineering diplomat obtained in 2017.

LANGUAGES -

- French
- English

DIVERSE

- The webmaster of the website of the Association of Anglophones of the National Advanced School of Engineering Yaoundé in 2015.
- Founder of the Music Club of the National Advanced School of Engineering Yaoundé.

CENTERS OF INTEREST —

Music, Drawing, Sports, Sciences, and Technological innovations.